<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Unikernel Alliance</title><link>/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Unikernel Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright (c) 2023 Hyas</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:12:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>bima</title><link>/projects/bima/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/bima/</guid><description>How can we package unikernels in the OCI image format?
To address this challenge, we created bima, a tool specifically designed for this purpose.</description></item><item><title>FlexOS</title><link>/projects/flexos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/flexos/</guid><description>FlexOS is a unikernel-based OS allowing users to easily specialize the safety and isolation strategy of an OS at compilation/deployment time, instead of design time.</description></item><item><title>HermiTux</title><link>/projects/hermitux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/hermitux/</guid><description>HermiTux is a unikernel binary-compatible with Linux: it can run native Linux executables. It supports multiple compiled (C, C++, Fortran) and interpreted (Python, LUA) languages.</description></item><item><title>Loupe</title><link>/projects/loupe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/loupe/</guid><description>Loupe is a tool designed to help collect and analyze the system call usage of an application. The tool can tell you what system calls need to be implemented in a custom OS to run the analyzed application, and visualize these numbers in a variety of plots.</description></item><item><title>OSv</title><link>/projects/osv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/osv/</guid><description>An open-source unikernel designed to run a single unmodified Linux application securely as microVM on top of a hypervisor, when compared to traditional operating systems which were designed for a vast range of physical machines.</description></item><item><title>Unikraft</title><link>/projects/unikraft/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/unikraft/</guid><description>Unikraft is a fast, secure and open source unikernel development kit. Unikraft powers the next-generation of cloud native applications by enabling you to radically customize and build custom OS/kernels, unlocking best-in-class performance, security primitives and efficiency savings.</description></item><item><title>urunc</title><link>/projects/urunc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/urunc/</guid><description>To bridge the gap between unikernels and traditional containerized environments, enabling seamless integration with cloud-native architectures, we introduce urunc. Designed to fully leverage the container semantics and benefit from the OCI tools and methodology, urunc aims to become “runc for unikernels”, while offering compatibility with the Container Runtime Interface (CRI).</description></item></channel></rss>