<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Unikernel Alliance</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Unikernel Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright (c) 2023 Hyas</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:33:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example Post</title><link>/blog/example-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:27:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>/blog/example-post/</guid><description/></item><item><title>bima</title><link>/projects/bima/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/bima/</guid><description>How can we package unikernels in the OCI image format?
To address this challenge, we created bima, a tool specifically designed for this purpose.</description></item><item><title>FlexOS</title><link>/projects/flexos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/flexos/</guid><description>FlexOS is a unikernel-based OS allowing users to easily specialize the safety and isolation strategy of an OS at compilation/deployment time, instead of design time.</description></item><item><title>Genezio</title><link>/projects/genezio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/genezio/</guid><description>genezio is a platform for developers to write and host a serverless application. You are writing your backend logic in classes and design your frontend using your preferred programming language.</description></item><item><title>Hermit</title><link>/projects/hermit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/hermit/</guid><description>Hermit is Rust-based, lightweight unikernel. It targets a scalable and predictable runtime for high-performance and cloud computing.
The ownership model of Rust guarantees memory/thread-safety and enables us to eliminate many classes of bugs at compile-time.</description></item><item><title>HermiTux</title><link>/projects/hermitux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/hermitux/</guid><description>HermiTux is a unikernel binary-compatible with Linux: it can run native Linux executables. It supports multiple compiled (C, C++, Fortran) and interpreted (Python, LUA) languages.</description></item><item><title>Loupe</title><link>/projects/loupe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/loupe/</guid><description>Loupe is a tool designed to help collect and analyze the system call usage of an application. The tool can tell you what system calls need to be implemented in a custom OS to run the analyzed application, and visualize these numbers in a variety of plots.</description></item><item><title>MirageOS</title><link>/projects/mirage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/mirage/</guid><description>MirageOS is a library operating system that constructs unikernels for secure, high-performance network applications across a variety of cloud computing and mobile platforms.</description></item><item><title>OSv</title><link>/projects/osv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/osv/</guid><description>OSv is an open-source unikernel designed to run a single unmodified Linux application securely as microVM on top of a hypervisor.</description></item><item><title>Toro Kernel</title><link>/projects/toro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:04:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>/projects/toro/</guid><description>Toro is a simple kernel that provides a dedicated API to develop microservices. We propose two kinds of sockets to build microservices: blocking and non-blocking.</description></item></channel></rss>